Tshepang Motloung

Naivasha Rd, Sunninghill, Sandton, 2157 079 317 9541 tamotloung@hotmail.co.za

Personal statement

A highly focused software developer with six years' work experience in software development and three years' experience in software testing. Organised, methodical and a keen eye for detail results in solid coding and trustworthy software programmes. Understanding client requirements and communicating the progress of projects are core values in achieving long lasting business relationships.

Core skills

Programming	Database	
C# (ASP.NET, MVC)	 SQL Server 	
Visual Basic .NET	 MySQL 	
	 MS Access 	
Object Relation Mapping	Web Services	
Entity Framework	 RESTful 	
 Dapper 		
Web		
■ HTML5	 JQuery 	
• CSS3	Razor	
 JavaScript 		

Angular

- Building Sections in our Policy Administration System that required redesigning and changes in process flows.
- Consuming web service from our internal API's.

TA Motloung 1 | Page

HTLM, Razor, CCS and JQuery

Building web applications.

Web Services

- Building services in C# using Entity Framework or Dapper.
- Integrating with external API's

Work history

Software Developer – <u>Oneplan (OneCard Management Services)</u> Sandon, Johannesburg (May 2015 – Present)

Duties

- Analysis of business requirements and creation of solution architecture to be deployed to a multi-server, load balanced environment using industry best practices.
- Database design and implementation using SQL Server 2019.
- Development of backend service layers using Web API.
 - Development of front-end applications using ASP.NET, MVC, JQuery, JavaScript and CSS
 - Mentorship of developers
 - Presenting ideas for system improvements, which results in company cost saving.
 - Designing and creating database tables to satisfy business requirements using best practice standards such as normalization forms.
 - Working closely with various departments in creating detailed specification and testing the product in controlled real situations before going live.
 - Maintaining the systems once they are up and running.
 - Creating Reports to assist management in decision making SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS).
 - Working closely with external companies with system(s) integration.
 - Conducting interviews for new software developers.

Quality Assurance Software Tester – <u>Securities Trading Technology</u>. Bedfordview, Johannesburg (October 2012 – April 2015)

As a QA Tester at STT I was presented with a piece of software and certain testing criteria. I evaluate, troubleshoot and test the software repeatedly in search of defects (bugs and errors).

TA Motloung 2 | Page

Duties

- Creating testing steps to recreate the defects identified, in so doing informing the developer as to where the defects are and possible causes.
- Voicing my opinion about what could simplify the end-users experience when using/interacting with our software to ensure not only defects free software but, to also ensure the our software is of the best quality in its target market.
 These problems with the software are then logged, prioritized and tracked by the programmers.
- Packaging Releases and\or patched to Clients. Using version control to ensure that the client receive the correct updated software.

Included in the Releases and\or patched are:

- ✓ Release Note that inform the client of the code that had been send to then, changes made buy the developer, and any areas that the changes may affect;
- ✓ Implementation Documentation that informs the client for the process to follow when Implementation the proved code;
- ✓ Test Packs that document the testing process.

Education

CTU Training Solutions Sandton

(2017 – Completed)

MCSD

- Completed 70-480: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3
- Completed 70-486: Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Applications

University of Johannesburg

(2007 – Incomplete)

BSc. in Information Technology

- Planning on registering for the Second Semester (2022) UNISA
- Pending Courses: Computer Science 2B, 3A and 3B

Riverlea Secondary School

(2000 - 2004)

English, Afrikaans, Mathematics (HG - B), Accounting (HG - C), Economics (HG - D), and Business Economics (SG - A)

TA Motloung 3 | Page

References

Team Leader and Senior Developer	Senior Developer
Telesure (1Life Insurance)	Oneplan
Mr. Ashveer Chirkoot	Mr. Robert Van Der Schyff
076 893 4705	072 691 9116
Software Engineer	Managing Director
Clientele	Ek-Solutions
Mr. Tsholo Nkuna	Mr. Elmar Klan
073 331 4008	074 117 1158

TA Motloung 4 | Page